Guide to the G. Evelyn Hutchinson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Research and Writings, 1922-1991; Series III
  - Articles and essays
    - "Ecological Biology in Relation to the Maintenance and Improvement of the Human Environment", 1967 (Box 63, Folder 97)
    - "A Note on the Genetics of Abraxas Grossulariata Ab. Fulvapicata Raynor", 1967 (Box 63, Folder 98)
    - "A Cambridge Caricaturist", 1968 (Box 63, Folder 99)
    - "When Are Species Necessary?", 1968 (Box 63, Folder 100)
    - "Aysheaia and the General Morphology of the Onychophora", 1969 (Box 63, Folder 101)
    - "Eutrophication: Past and Present", 1969 (Box 63, Folder 102)
    - "Some Continental European Aberrations of Abraxas Grossulariata Linn. (Lepidoptera) with a Note on the Theoretical Significance of the Variation Observed in the Species", 1969 (Box 63, Folder 103)
    - "The Biosphere", 1970 (Box 63, Folder 104)
    - "The Chemical Ecology of Three Species of Myriophyllum Angiospermae, Haloragaceae)", 1970 (Box 63, Folder 105)
    - Ianula: An Account of the History and Development of the Lago di Monterosi, Latium, Italy
      - "Introductory Account of the Basin", 1970 (Box 63, Folder 106)
      - "Chemistry and Mineralogy of the Sediments and Their Source Materials", 1970 (Box 63, Folder 107)
      - "The History of the Lake: A Synthesis", 1970 (Box 63, Folder 108)
    - "The 'Idol' or Sheela na gig at Binstead", 1970 (Box 64, Folder 109)
    - "Marginalia", 1970 (Box 64, Folder 110)
    - "Marginalia. Wisdom is Justified of All Her Children", 1970 (Box 64, Folder 111)
    - "Scale Effects in Ecology" [from banquet address to the International Symposium on Statistical Ecology, 1969], 1971 (Box 64, Folder 112)
    - "Marginalia. Long Meg Reconsidered" [parts 1 and 2], 1972 (Box 64, Folder 113)
    - Review: Nutrients and Eutrophication, 1972 (Box 64, Folder 114)
    - "Marginalia. Eutrophication", 1973 (Box 64, Folder 115)
    - "Sodium Dynamics in a Northern Ecosystem", 1973 (Box 64, Folder 116)
    - "The Waters of Merom: A Study of Lake Huleh. III. The Major Chemical Constituents of a 54m. Core", 1973 (Box 64, Folder 117-122)
    - "Attitudes Toward Nature in Medieval England: The Alphonso and Bird Psalters" [based on the Saxton Memorial Lecture], 1974 (Box 65, Folder 123-124)
    - "De Rebus Planctonicis", 1974 (Box 65, Folder 125)
    - "Marginalia. Apostemic Insects and the Master of the Brussels Initials", 1974 (Box 65, Folder 126-127)
    - "New and Inadequately Described Aberrations of Abraxas Grossulariata (Linn.) (Lep.: Geometridae)", 1974 (Box 65, Folder 128)
    - "For What Sort of Life Should Mankind Aim?", 1975 (Box 65, Folder 129)
    - "Mammalia in the Hunting Scene from Dura Mithraeum", 1975 (Box 65, Folder 130)
    - "Some Biological Analogies", 1975 (Box 65, Folder 131)
    - "Variations on a Theme by Robert MacArthur", 1975 (Box 65, Folder 132)
    - "Marginalia. Man Talking and Thinking", 1976 (Box 66, Folder 133)
    - "A Taste for Learning", 1976 (Box 66, Folder 134)
    - "The Influence of the New World on the Study of Natural History", 1977 (Box 66, Folder 135)
    - "Memorial: George Alfred Baitsell, 1885 1971", 1977 (Box 66, Folder 136)
    - Review: Island Biology Illustrated by the Land Birds of Jamaica, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 137)
    - "Science Has Been Liberal Handed", 1977 (Box 66, Folder 138)
    - "Thoughts on $370 Million", 1977 (Box 66, Folder 139)
    - "The Waters of Merom: A Study of Lake Huleh. V. Temporal Changes in Molluscan Fauna", 1977 (Box 66, Folder 140-141)
    - "Scanning Electron Microscope Study of Palar Pegs of Three Species of Corixidae (Hemiptera)", 1978 (Box 66, Folder 142)
    - "Sexual Dimorphism in Winter Whitening of the Stoat Mustela Erminea", 1978 (Box 66, Folder 143)
    - "Zoological Iconography in the West after A.D. 1200", 1978 (Box 66, Folder 144)
    - "Historical Introduction"[in Problems of Genetics ], 1979 (Box 66, Folder 145)
    - "Memories of the Corixid Water Bugs", 1979 (Box 66, Folder 146)
    - Review: Prehistoric Avebury; (Aubrey Burl); Megalithic Remains in Britain and Brittany (A. Thom and A. S. Thom); Megaliths and Masterminds (Peter Lancaster Brown), 1979 (Box 66, Folder 147)
    - Review: Survivals of Greek Zoological Illuminations in Byzantine Manuscripts (Zoltán Kádár), 1979 (Box 66, Folder 148)
    - "Conjectures Arising in a Quiet Museum", 1980 (Box 66, Folder 149)
    - "Lorande Loss Woodruff, 1879 1947", 1980 (Box 66, Folder 150)
    - Letter to the editors. "Where Is Everybody?", 1981 (Box 66, Folder 151)
    - Review: The Gardens of Pompeii, 1981 (Box 66, Folder 152)
    - "Thoughts on Aquatic Insects", 1981 (Box 67, Folder 153)
    - "Views. Random Adaptation and Imitation in Human Evolution", 1981 (Box 67, Folder 154)
    - "The Harp that Once...A Note on the Discovery of Stridulation in the Corixid Water Bugs", 1982 (Box 67, Folder 155)
    - "Life in Air and Water" [based on 1981 Othniel Charles Marsh lecture], 1982 (Box 67, Folder 156-157)
    - "Reminiscences and Notes on Some Otherwise Undiscussed Papers", 1982 (Box 67, Folder 158)
    - Review: Birds in Medieval Manuscripts, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 159)
    - Review: The Monstrous Races in Medieval Art and Thought, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 160)
    - "The Waters of Merom: A Study of Lake Huleh. VIII. Non siliceous Plant Remains with Appendices on Some Animal Fossils", 1982 (Box 67, Folder 161)
    - "Marginalia. What Is Science For?", 1983 (Box 67, Folder 162)
    - "Letter to the Editor. The Possible Adaptive Significance of the Brooks Dyar Rule", 1984 (Box 68, Folder 163)
    - "Letter to the Editor. Unexplained Dogma", 1984 (Box 68, Folder 164)
    - "In Memoriam. Gordon Riley, 1911 1985", 1986 (Box 68, Folder 165)
    - "The Ecological Niche", 1987 (Box 68, Folder 166)
    - "Introduction to: The Strange Necessity ", 1987 (Box 68, Folder 167)
    - "Keep Walking" [based on the lecture for the 1986 Kyoto Prize], 1987 (Box 68, Folder 168)
    - Review: Angels Fear, 1988 (Box 68, Folder 169)
    - "W. Thomas Edmondson", 1988 (Box 68, Folder 170)
    - "Robert Helmer MacArthur (1930 1972)", 1989 (Box 68, Folder 171)
    - "The Role of A. N. Formozov in the Development of Ecological Theory", 1989 (Box 68, Folder 172)
    - "Alexander Petrunkevitch, 1875 1964", 1991 (Box 68, Folder 173)
    - "Libbie Henrietta Hyman, 1888 1969", 1991 (Box 68, Folder 174)
  - Books
    - The Clear Mirror
      - Drafts, fragments, notes, undated (Box 68, Folder 175-176)
      - Reviews, 1936-1938, 1953-1958 (Box 68, Folder 177)
      - "Introduction" to a new edition, 1978 (Box 69, Folder 178)
    - Ecological Theatre and the Evolutionary Play
      - Early version, undated (Box 69, Folder 179-180)
      - Drafts, undated (Box 69, Folder 181-183)
      - Typescript, 1965 (Box 69, Folder 184)
      - Reviews, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 185)
    - Enchanted Voyage
      - Drafts, undated (Box 69, Folder 186)
      - Reviews, 1963 (Box 69, Folder 187)
    - Introduction to Population Ecology
      - Transcript of lectures for course, Ecological Principles
        - I-X, undated (Box 69, Folder 188-189)
        - XI-XXVIII, undated (Box 70, Folder 190-192)
      - First draft
        - undated (Box 70, Folder 193-203)
        - undated (Box 71, Folder 204-210)
      - Revised chapters of draft, undated (Box 71, Folder 211-212)
      - Typescript
        - Chapters I-IV, undated (Box 71, Folder 213-214)
        - Chapters V-VI and captions for figures, undated (Box 72, Folder 215-217)
      - Revised pages of typescript, undated (Box 72, Folder 218)
      - Final typescript
        - Chapters I-VI, undated (Box 72, Folder 219-223)
        - Appendix and indices, undated (Box 73, Folder 224-225)
      - Production details and publicity, 1976 1978 (Box 73, Folder 226)
      - Reviews, 1978-1981 (Box 73, Folder 227)
    - Itinerant Ivory Tower
      - Original schemata, undated (Box 73, Folder 228)
      - Drafts, undated (Box 73, Folder 229)
      - Reviews, 1953 (Box 73, Folder 230)
        See also: Series III, box 68, Folder 177
    - Kindly Fruits of the Earth
      - Background material, 1924 1926, 1939, 1958 (Box 73, Folder 231)
      - Drafts
        - undated (Box 73, Folder 232-235)
        - undated (Box 74, Folder 236-244)
      - Fragments, undated (Box 75, Folder 245-246)
      - Publicity, 1978-1979 (Box 75, Folder 247)
      - Reviews, 1979-1980 (Box 75, Folder 248)
    - Treatise on Limnology
      - General [drafts of sections, notes fragments for, undated (Box 75, Folder 249-259)
      - Volume I
        - Chapters 1-2, 11-12, 17 [drafts, notes ], undated (Box 76, Folder 260-264)
        - Drafts of sections, notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 265-268)
        - Publicity, reviews, 1957-1959 (Box 76, Folder 269)
      - Volume II
        - Outlines, notes on organization, undated (Box 76, Folder 270)
        - Original manuscript draft, undated (Box 76, Folder 271-273)
        - Drafts
          - Chapters 18, 20, 23, undated (Box 76, Folder 274-279)
          - Chapters 20-23, 25-26, undated (Box 77, Folder 280-287)
        - Notes, fragments, undated (Box 78, Folder 288-300)
        - Reviews, 1966 1968, 1976 (Box 78, Folder 301)
      - Volume III
        - Outlines, notes on organizational structure, undated (Box 78, Folder 302)
        - Complete first version, undated (Box 78, Folder 303-305)
        - Early draft, undated (Box 79, Folder 306)
        - Lacustrine endemism drafts, undated (Box 79, Folder 307-308)
        - Chapter 30 draft, undated (Box 79, Folder 309-310)
        - Notes, drafts of sections, fragments, undated (Box 79, Folder 311-318)
        - Illustrations, undated (Box 80, Folder 319)
        - Final rough manuscript, undated (Box 80, Folder 320-326)
        - Reviews, 1975-1977 (Box 80, Folder 327)
      - Volume IV
        - Outlines, notes on organizational structure, 1986-1988, undated (Box 81, Folder 328)
        - Editorial correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 81, Folder 329-331)
        - Preliminary notes, drafts, undated (Box 81, Folder 332)
        - Preface, acknowledgments, 1987-1991, undated (Box 81, Folder 333-334)
        - Chapter 33, undated (Box 81, Folder 335)
        - Chapter 34, 1987-1988, undated
          - Handwritten sections, undated (Box 81, Folder 336)
          - Handwritten sections, undated (Box 82, Folder 337-339)
          - Working copy, undated (Box 82, Folder 340-342)
          - Typescript, undated (Box 82, Folder 343-345)
          - Typescript drafts, undated (Box 83, Folder 346)
          - Typescript of sections, undated (Box 83, Folder 347-349)
          - Notes, fragments, undated (Box 83, Folder 350-351)
        - Chapter 35, undated
          - Handwritten sections, undated (Box 83, Folder 352-356)
          - Typescript, undated (Box 83, Folder 357-358)
          - Notes, fragments, undated (Box 84, Folder 359)
        - Chapter 36, [circa 1990] (Box 84, Folder 360)
        - Chapter 37, undated
          - Handwritten sections, undated (Box 84, Folder 361-365)
          - Handwritten sections, undated (Box 85, Folder 366)
          - Typescript, undated (Box 85, Folder 367-373)
          - Figures, undated (Box 85, Folder 374)
          - Notes, fragments, undated (Box 85, Folder 375-376)
        - Chapter 38, undated
          - Notes on organization, undated (Box 86, Folder 377)
          - Handwritten sections, figures, undated (Box 86, Folder 378-385)
          - Revisions for "Biology of the Corixoidea", undated (Box 87, Folder 386-387)
          - Typescript, undated (Box 87, Folder 388-395)
          - Typescript, undated (Box 88, Folder 396-398)
          - Notes, fragments, undated (Box 88, Folder 399)
  - Lectures and speeches
    - Connecticut Academy, [193-] (Box 88, Folder 400)
    - "The Carbon Metabolism of the Earth and Some Related Biological Problems", 1941 April 5 (Box 88, Folder 401)
    - Wesleyan University, [194-] (Box 88, Folder 402)
    - Volterra type oscillation, [1952 or 1953] (Box 88, Folder 403)
    - "Looking at Nature: 1280 1480" [AAAS meeting], 1968 (Box 88, Folder 404)
    - Tribute to Ruth Patrick, 1969 (Box 88, Folder 405)
    - Ohio State, 1970 November (Box 88, Folder 406)
    - Boston University workshop on the problems of population control, 1970 (Box 88, Folder 407)
    - "Killing Cockroaches Is Not Enough" [AAAS meeting, Philadelphia], 1971 December (Box 88, Folder 408)
    - "Geochemical Background of Ecology," Bangor, 1972 July (Box 88, Folder 409)
    - University of Pennsylvania; Philadelphia Academy, 1972 October (Box 88, Folder 410)
    - "Some Biological Analogies" [Limits to Growth lecture series, Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies], 1972 November 14 (Box 88, Folder 411)
    - Presentation of the Cottrell Award to W. Thomas Edmondson, 1973 April 23 (Box 88, Folder 412)
    - "The Next Few Steps in Ecology," University of Rhode Island, [1973 or 1974] (Box 88, Folder 413)
    - Tyler Award acceptance speech, 1974 February 8 (Box 88, Folder 414)
    - "Remarks on Problems Relating to the Preservation of Biological Diversity" [World Wildlife Fund meeting], 1974 March 27 (Box 88, Folder 415)
    - Yale Science and Engineering Association, 1974 April 1 (Box 88, Folder 416)
    - Cottrell Award, [1974] (Box 88, Folder 417)
    - Wilbur Cross High School, 1977 March 2 (Box 88, Folder 418)
    - Population Biologists of New England, 1977 (Box 88, Folder 419)
    - "Fifty Years in the OML", 1978 November 20 (Box 89, Folder 420)
    - Anthropology, 1979 January 16 (Box 89, Folder 421)
    - Franklin Medal, 1979 October 24 (Box 89, Folder 422)
    - Woods Hole Oceanographic Laboratory, 1984 September 10 (Box 89, Folder 423)
    - Alumni Day symposium, undated (Box 89, Folder 424)
    - ASLO, New York, undated (Box 89, Folder 425)
    - Cambridge, undated (Box 89, Folder 426)
    - Future of the Yale Graduate School, undated (Box 89, Folder 427)
    - Jonathan Edwards College seminar on writing popular science, undated (Box 89, Folder 428)
    - Pallanza, undated (Box 89, Folder 429)
    - Rockefeller University, undated (Box 89, Folder 430)
    - Untitled outlines, undated (Box 89, Folder 431)
  - Notes
    - Abraxas, undated (Box 89, Folder 432-435)
    - African and Indian waterbugs, undated (Box 89, Folder 436)
    - Alkalies and alkaline earths, undated (Box 89, Folder 437)
    - Aquatic bugs, [circa 1929] (Box 89, Folder 438)
    - Atoms per cell computation, undated (Box 90, Folder 439)
    - Biogeochemistry, undated (Box 90, Folder 440-442)
    - Chemical determination, undated (Box 90, Folder 443)
    - Chemical ecology of the Cladocera: protocols of experiments, undated (Box 90, Folder 444)
    - Collecting, 1925-1926 (Box 90, Folder 445)
    - Collecting, North America [some in hand of Grace Pickford], undated (Box 90, Folder 446)
    - Corixidae, undated (Box 90, Folder 447)
    - Ecology, general, undated (Box 90, Folder 448)
    - Embryology, undated (Box 90, Folder 449)
    - Embryology course, undated (Box 90, Folder 450)
    - Entomology of high mountains in Switzerland, undated (Box 90, Folder 451)
    - Freshwater ecology in South Africa [with Grace Pickford and J. F. M. Schurman], undated (Box 90, Folder 452)
    - Geochemistry, undated (Box 90, Folder 453)
    - Goa, undated (Box 90, Folder 454)
    - Guano, undated (Box 90, Folder 455-458)
    - Guernsey archaeology, n1925, o date (Box 91, Folder 459)
    - Hemiptera, [circa 1950] (Box 91, Folder 460-461)
    - Hemiptera Heteroptera, undated (Box 91, Folder 462)
    - Indian Tibetan lakes, undated (Box 91, Folder 463)
    - King, Edward, undated (Box 91, Folder 464)
    - Lago di Monterosi, undated (Box 91, Folder 465-469)
    - Lake Huleh
      - 1968-1969 (Box 91, Folder 470-473)
      - 1970-1975, undated (Box 92, Folder 474-477)
    - Lake sediments, undated (Box 92, Folder 478)
    - Lakes, undated (Box 92, Folder 479)
    - Lillie, D. G., undated (Box 92, Folder 480)
    - Limnological methods: physico chemical field records, 1938-1939 (Box 92, Folder 481)
    - Limnology course, undated (Box 92, Folder 482)
    - Limnology lectures, 1941 (Box 92, Folder 483)
    - Linsley Pond, 1937-1939 (Box 93, Folder 484-487)
    - Lithium, undated (Box 93, Folder 488)
    - Logistic with time lag, undated (Box 93, Folder 489)
    - Maimonides' flora and fauna, undated (Box 93, Folder 490)
    - Mustela Erminea, undated (Box 93, Folder 491)
    - Natural history of animals course [Zoology 24b], undated (Box 93, Folder 492)
    - Nitrogen, 1925, 1931, undated (Box 93, Folder 493)
    - Pine Orchard temperature data, 1946-1957 (Box 93, Folder 494)
    - Pollen data sheets, undated (Box 93, Folder 495)
    - Principles of ecology course [Zoology 172], undated (Box 93, Folder 496)
    - Radioactive elements, natural, undated (Box 93, Folder 497)
    - Rotifers, undated (Box 94, Folder 498-499)
    - Shells, undated (Box 94, Folder 500)
    - Shepherd ivories, undated (Box 94, Folder 501)
    - Tynan Purple, undated (Box 94, Folder 502)
    - Vitamin work, undated (Box 94, Folder 503)
    - Willis' effect, 1922 (Box 94, Folder 504)
    - Zoological, undated (Box 94, Folder 505)
    - Unsorted
      - Oversize (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - undated (Box 94, Folder 506-514)
      - undated (Box 95, Folder 515-526)
  - Research notebooks [collected data, observations]
    - Oversize (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - 1924-1940 (Box 95, Folder 527-529)
    - 1940-1951, undated (Box 96, Folder 530-537)
  - Writings, unpublished
    - Yale Alumni Magazine piece, undated (Box 97, Folder 538)
    - "The Animal in Search of Its Individuality" [with Allison Bishop Jolly], undated (Box 97, Folder 539-540)
    - "Anne book", [circa 1987] (Box 97, Folder 541)
    - "Anisops (Hemiptera: Notonectidae) collected by the Yale North India Expedition)", undated (Box 97, Folder 542)
    - Aquatic insects, undated (Box 97, Folder 543)
    - "The Atmosphere", undated (Box 97, Folder 544)
    - Atmospheres, 1950, undated (Box 97, Folder 545-548)
    - "The Biochemistry of the Atmosphere", undated (Box 97, Folder 549)
    - Biogeochemistry, undated (Box 98, Folder 550)
    - "Biogeochemistry of Iodine and Bromine", undated (Box 98, Folder 551-553)
    - "The Biologist Looks at Cultural Anthropology", undated (Box 98, Folder 554)
    - Biosphere, undated (Box 98, Folder 555)
    - "The Bottomless Lake: A Note on Some Scientific Imagery in the Poetry of Edith Sitwell", undated (Box 98, Folder 556)
    - "Composition, analyse and study of the products of the Colony", 1929 (Box 98, Folder 557)
    - "Copper Meteorites", undated (Box 98, Folder 558)
    - "Cosmochemistry and Geochemistry", undated (Box 98, Folder 559)
    - "David Forbes and Guano Archaeology", [circa 1948] (Box 98, Folder 560)
    - Ecological principles, extreme habitats, undated (Box 98, Folder 561)
    - "Edward Smith Deevey" [for National Academy of Sciences Biographical Memoirs ], [circa 1989] (Box 98, Folder 562)
    - "Epiphytic Waters", undated (Box 98, Folder 563)
    - "The Future of Marine Paleoecology", undated (Box 98, Folder 564)
    - Gates, G. E., undated (Box 98, Folder 565)
    - "Guano: An Account of the Purely Scientific Significance of the Droppings of Sea Birds", undated (Box 98, Folder 566)
    - Halogens, undated (Box 98, Folder 567)
    - Heraldry, undated (Box 98, Folder 568)
    - "Introduction to Wicken Fen", undated (Box 98, Folder 569)
    - "A List of the Fauna of the Root of King's College Chapel", undated (Box 98, Folder 570)
    - "Method of Applying Turbulence Law to a Set of Lake Temperatures", undated (Box 98, Folder 571)
    - "The Morphology and Genetics of Partial Situs Inversus in the Mexican Waterbug Krizousacorixa Femorta (Guer.)", undated (Box 98, Folder 572)
    - Mortimer criticisms, [circa 1973] (Box 98, Folder 573)
    - "The Natural History of Lake Avernus", 1926 (Box 98, Folder 574)
    - "A note on adaptive pterygopolymorphism in Micronecta (Corixidae)" [festschrift for Edward Deevey, Jr.], 1987 (Box 98, Folder 575)
    - "Note on Australian Lacustrine Monocot", undated (Box 98, Folder 576)
    - "A Note on Ornithological Decoration in Opus Anglicanum", 1972, undated (Box 98, Folder 577)
    - "Notes on Bugs, Mostly Aquatic, from the Isle of Man", 1923 (Box 98, Folder 578)
    - "Notes on Certain Monuments in Portuguese India", undated (Box 98, Folder 579)
    - "Notes on People We Have Known in New Haven", undated (Box 98, Folder 580)
    - "Notes on the Palearctic Species of Notonecta L (Hemiptera Heteroptera)", undated (Box 98, Folder 581)
    - "Notes on the Recurrence of Spontaneous Fish Mortality in a Pond in Connecticut", undated (Box 99, Folder 582)
    - "On Fugitive Species", undated (Box 99, Folder 583)
    - "Oxygen deficient paper", undated (Box 99, Folder 584)
    - "Periodicity in Tropical and Subtropical Inland Waters", undated (Box 99, Folder 585)
    - Phosphorus, undated (Box 99, Folder 586)
    - "The Problems of Oceanographic Geochemistry", undated (Box 99, Folder 587)
    - "Radiochromatography of Protein Hydrolysates", undated (Box 99, Folder 588)
    - Rebecca West reader, undated (Box 99, Folder 589)
    - "A Reconsideration of the Carbon Cycle", 1951 (Box 99, Folder 590)
    - "The Scientific Work of John Langston Brooks", undated (Box 99, Folder 591)
    - "Sexual Behavior of Birds", [circa 1925] (Box 99, Folder 592)
    - Soal, S. G., [circa 1960] (Box 99, Folder 593)
    - "Stratigraphic and Developmental Studies on Individual Lakes", undated (Box 99, Folder 594)
    - "Studies on Asymmetry I. On Partial Reversal of Asymmetry in Related Species of Animals", [circa 1930] (Box 99, Folder 595)
    - "Sweet Are the Uses of Diversity", 1985 (Box 99, Folder 596)
    - "The Temperamental Ecology of Deer Mice", undated (Box 99, Folder 597)
    - "The Temporal Traveler", 1939 (Box 99, Folder 598)
    - "The Twelve Apostles", [circa 1923] (Box 99, Folder 599)
    - "Two Middle Cambrian Animals Described by C. D. Walcott", undated (Box 99, Folder 600)
    - "Variations of the Hemipteron Philaneus Spumarius L.", undated (Box 99, Folder 601)
    - Whittlesford church alabasters, 1967, undated (Box 99, Folder 602)
    - Book reviews, 1942-1987 (Box 99, Folder 603)
      See also: Series I, folder 618
    - Illustrations, undated (Box 99, Folder 604)
    - Letters to the editor, 1970-1987 (Box 99, Folder 605)
    - Plays, poems, spoofs, student papers, [circa 192- -194-] (Box 99, Folder 606)
    - Loose pages, 1955, undated (Box 100, Folder 607-619)
    - Loose pages, 1955, undated (Box 101, Folder 620-631)
- Personal Files, 1916-1991; Series IV
  This series contains Hutchinson's personal papers, which include biographical information and materials relating to his family history, his parents and his wives. There are also numerous files documenting awards and honors Hutchinson received and celebrations in his honor. The memorabilia files also include a scrapbook of photographs and drawings from Hutchinson's early travels in Italy. Student notebooks in the series date from Hutchinson's years at Cambridge University.
  - Appointment books, 1974, 1976 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Art collection, 1973, 1989, undated (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Articles and clippings about Hutchinson, [194-]-1985 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Awards, citations, honors
    - General, 1949-1974 (Box 102, Folder 4)
      - Oversize (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Lawrence College [honorary degree], 1954 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Princeton University [honorary degree], 1961 (Box 102, Folder 6)
      - Oversize (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - New Haven Festival of the Arts, 1966 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Niagara University [honorary degree], 1969 (Box 102, Folder 8)
      - Oversize (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Browning Award, 1971 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Washington University [honorary degree], 1972 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - William Clyde DeVane Award, 1972 (Box 102, Folder 11)